<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech stuff on Album.blog()</title>
    <link>https://albumblog.github.io/en/tech/2020/08/25/windows-some-considerations/</link>
    <description>Recent contents in "Tech stuff" on Album.blog()</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Alberto &#34;Album&#34; Buffolino</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 12:20:23</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://albumblog.github.io/en/tech/2020/08/25/windows-some-considerations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Windows: some considerations (a very old joke)</title>
      <link>https://albumblog.github.io/en/tech/2020/08/25/windows-some-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 14:00:42</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://albumblog.github.io/en/tech/2020/08/25/windows-some-considerations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poor Windows&amp;hellip; with 10 has become a quite stable system, but its reputation remains unchanged, at least since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IW7Rqwwth84&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the infamous BSOD during Windows 98 presentation&lt;/a&gt; (another very old, organized joke, indeed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, despite I always used this one as my personal system (firstly for accessibility reasons), I like sharing here an old IT joke about it, found in Internet years and years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Windows a virus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, Windows is not a virus. Here&amp;rsquo;s what viruses do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They replicate quickly - okay, Windows does that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viruses use up valuable system resources, slowing down the system as they do so - okay, Windows does that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viruses will, from time to time, trash your hard disk - okay, Windows does that too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viruses are usually carried, unknown to the user, along with valuable programs and systems - sigh&amp;hellip; Windows does that, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viruses will occasionally make the user suspect their system is too slow (see 2) and the user will buy new hardware - yup, Windows does that, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now it seems Windows is a virus but there are fundamental differences: viruses are well supported by their authors, are running on most systems, their program code is fast, compact and efficient and they tend to become more sophisticated as they mature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Windows is not a virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🦋&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
